CHUN-HAO HUANG (JACK HUANG)

A highly motivated and passionate software engineer from Carnegie Mellon University, offering 2 years of experience in the full-stack development life-cycle – from concept through delivery of state of the art applications to real-world challenges.

Education

Carnegie Mellon University

Sep. 2021 - Exp. Dec. 2022

Master of Science in Software Engineering - Applied Study

Mountain View, CA

Selected Coursework: Foundation of Software Engineering, Foundation of Computer Systems, Mobile and IoT security.

National Cheng Kung University

Sep. 2016 - Jun. 2020

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Information Engineering (GPA: 3.86/4.00)

Tainan, Taiwan

Selected Coursework: Programming Languages (A+), Algorithms (A+), Data Structure (A), Advanced Competitive Programming (A).

Work Experience

Co-founder & Full-stack Engineer | Vue.js, Cordova, AWS, Docker, GitLab CI/CD

Nov. 2019 - Present

CityChaser (Shortlisted in 2020 U-Start Plan for Innovation and Entrepreneurship, 75 out of 500+ applications.)
Taipei, Taiwan
Shortened app development cycle by proposing and integrating Apache Cordova into project to build a one-codebase hybrid mobile app (Android & iOS).

- Boosted map render/update frame rate by 200% by building Cordova native plugin with Mapbox SDK.
- Implemented exponential backoff algorithm using Axios interceptors during peak period to avoid excessive load to API server.
- Introduced DevOps pipelines using GitLab CI/CD and Docker for Android automatic deployment in semantic versioning under Gitflow and thus shortened deployment cycle time by 50%.
- Led 10-person cross-functional team as a Scrum master coordinating Sprint Planning, Daily Stand-ups, Sprint retrospectives, Sprint Demos, and Release Planning resulting in on-time delivery rate of 95%.
- Designed and built core for games including collecting resources, mining, offline countdown timer, etc.
- Constructed several back-end APIs including collect resource system, email system using Express.js, DynamoDB, AWS Lambda.

Web Development Intern | JQuery, Django, PostgreSQL, Apache, Kerberos

Jul. 2019 - Aug. 2019

IT Department, FarEasTone Telecom (The 2nd largest telecom operator in Taiwan)

New Taipei, Taiwan

- Implemented responsive web UI adopting Responsive Web Design approach to enrich mobile and desktop browsing experience.
- Reduced HR daily workload by 13% by creating scripts to automate monthly KPI reports generating process.
- Guided 3-person team and completed a project 2 weeks earlier, writing a 13-page handover note.
- Proposed AAA (Authentication, Authorization, and Accounting) secure transport protocol using Kerberos and Microsoft Active Directory for identity validation of non-secure network communication.

Selected Projects

Online Judge and Game Integrated System | Vue.js, Vuetify, Express.js, Redis, MongoDB, Firejail, Nginx Jan. 2020 - Jun. 2020
Constructed an online judge system and content manage system for coding problem management, evaluating 300+ students' performance in Program Design (I) course in 2020 at National Cheng Kung University.

ATG.io | Vue.js, Element-UI, GIN, LevelDB, Redis, Konva, pako, Docker, Kubernetes, GCP, PyTorch

Jan. 2019 - Aug. 2019

- Trained a bot agent via both Deep Q-network in reinforcement learning paradigm and real-time training with users' logic in C++.
- Developed a real-time web-based platform allowing users to upload C++ code and to run simulations.

HackMDir | React.js, Redux, Webpack, Babel, Material-UI, ESLint, Google Chrome API

Jan. 2019 - Jun. 2019

• Created a chrome extension with DOM injection and cookie/header exploitation to enhance user experience for HackMD regular users with directory categorization and bulk operation, earning an internship offer from HackMD CTO.

Achievements

- 2nd prize in 2019 MeiChu Hackathon (out of 34 teams from top Taiwan universities).
- 3rd prize in Mobile Game Development track of 2020 Vision Get Wild Award (out of 53 teams from universities across Taiwan).
- FutureTech Breakthrough Award in 2020 Future Tech exhibition (71 out of 600+ applications from universities across Taiwan).

Leadership

Chief of IT Department at 2019 NCKU Bike Festival (The largest college fair in southern Taiwan)

Oct. 2018 - Mar. 2019

• Promoted college fair by developing official website with content management system recapping latest educational information, attained 48,043 pageviews and 24,244 visitors for website cumulatively.

Skills

Programming/Scripting Languages: (Proficient) JavaScript, Python, (Experienced) C/C++, Java, ShellScript, Golang. **Tools/Frameworks**: Qt, Vue.js, React.js, Django, Express.js, MongoDB, GraphQL, Git, PyTorch, Docker, Kubernetes. **Clouds**: Heroku, Firebase, Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud Platform.